Guide to the Josiah K. Lilly Correspondence, 1931-1944 CAM.JKLCorr.2016
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- H, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1076)
  Correspondence with Charles J. Haden; Georgine Hagenbuch; G.E. Haight; Lavern H. Hakes; Beulah Hale; Marjorie Hall; William M. Hall; Walter W. Haller; W.W. Haller; Jesse Halsey; Alma Hamilton; W.M. Hamilton; Hammond Instrument Company; Floyd H. Hanson; Charles R. Harbaugh; Ida M. Harless; Frank C. Harper; Jessie M. Harper; Joseph H. Harper; Bernard Harrell; Evaline Harrington; Hugh Harris; J.V. Harris; William H. Harrold; Jackie Harser; Idam ae Harshbarger; Kenneth Hartman; Kenneth Hartman; Dallas S. Harvey; M.M. Haskell; H.F. Hasse; William E. Hassinger; Herbert Hathaway; Viola Hattjar; Louise Hauser; A.C. Hayes; Anna M.J. Hayes; Harrison J. Hays; Charles Haywood; Charles Haywood; J. Alexander Heer; John A. Heer; Calvin A. Heiges; George L. Heiges; Ruth A. Heigley; Clifford S. Heinz; Howard Heinz; Omar C. Held; Essie Helmick; June E. Hemstreet; K.E. Hendershot; Catherine Henderson; James A. Henderson; Claude O. Hendricks; J. Hendrix; H. de S. Henley; Bernice Henny; William S. Henry; Paul Hensarling; Richard Hensinger; maude Herring; Howard Hertweck; Maurice Herzberger; Edward P. Hewlings; James C. Hicks; Vincent Hiden; Hieronyme; James W. Higgins; W.R. Higgins; William Robert Higgins; Patricia Hilansky; Henry H. Hill; Howard P. Hill; John J. Hill; Harold E. Hillenberg; Patricia Hilovsky; Neil E. Hinkle; Charles Hippert; Historical and Philosphical Society of Ohio; Meitha Hiteman; Baxter E. Hobgood; Mildred Hockenberry; W.D. Hockensmith; Bradford H. Hodges; Fletcher Hodges; Francis T. Hodges; Moorhead B. Holland; Paul C. Hollinger; Patricia Ann Hontz; Glenn L. Hook; Hoosier Motor Club; Dorothea Hope; Joseph Horne; Frances Horwath; Laurier House; Gabriel Houston; Joan Houston; James H. Howell; Thaddeus Hrinko; Floyd Hughett; Arthur B. Hull; George Humbert; Louise Humphreys; A.B. Hunt; Roy A. Hunt; Lewis E. Husemen; Jackie Huskey; William R. Hutchinson; David Hyde; Thomas K. Hymers
- Howard, John Tasker, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1077)
  Correspondence with John Tasker Howard of Glen Ridge, NJ. In 1932 Howard was a musicologist with one book to his credit. He earned additional income by lecturing around the country and hosting a radio show. Howard and Lilly met for the first time in Nov, 1932. By Dec. 1932 Howard was working on the Foster biography, receiving a small stipend from Lilly for support during his research. Howard was rapidly accepted by the Foster Hall staff. The biography was published in Jan. 1934. The correspondence during this year is rich with gossip as well as opinions and reviews of the many plays and movies which were being produced that season. Howard was having legal difficulties at this time. His publishers were withholding permission for Howard to dramatize the biography which he hoped to have Gene Raymond direct. The 1935-38 correspondence holds an enormous quantity of letters about the Foster house controversy, verification that Foster lived in Hoboken; Howard's arrangements of Foster s songs; Maskell Ewing's death. Also a lot of notes between Howard and Hodges pointing out errors in the biography.
- Indianapolis Photo Company, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1078)
- J, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1079)
  Correspondence with Joan Jackell; Rilba Evelyn Jackman; Joanne Jackman; Diana Jackman; Rilba Evelyn Jackman; Elmer C. Jackson; William Jackson; Maxine Jackson; V.G. Jackson; Jackson Township Schools; Paul R. James; James Book Store; William Jamison; Fanny Jenkins; Jenkins Music Co.; Donald F. Johnson; Ed Johnson; Harold G. Johnson; Helen P. Johnson; Elizabeth Johnston; Dolores R. Jones; Edmund Caye Jones; Forrest E. Jones; Jessie W. Jones; John G. Jones; Mirriam Jones; Caroline C. Jourdan; Caroline C. Jourdan
- K, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1080)
  Correspondence with Hugo Kahl; Ermine Kahn; Martha Kane; Thomas A. M. Kane; Thomas C. Kane; Henrietta Kauehl; Edgar Kaufmann; Victor Kaufman; Sammy Kaye; Keasler and Clarke; Everett Keefer; W. Lloyd Keepers; Mildred S. Keesey; Vincent Keesey; Henrietta Kaiser; Lorraine Kelafont; William F. Kelleher; Jeane J. Kelley; Donald J. Kelly; Donald S. Kelly; John T. Kelly; Jennie Kelton; L.W. Kemmish; Bob Kennedy; Mary Kenneth; Charles A. Kent; Jack Alan Keru; Agnetta F. Kerns; Hugh T. Kerr; Edith Kershner; Keystone Picture Frame Co.; Kielsmeier; Laura C. Kilburn; Wilma J. Killion; Clara Kimball; Harry J. Kimball; Russell W. Kimble; Oscar Kincaid; Gerald King; W.L. King; Henrietta M. Kinsey; Charles P. Kirkinson; H.B. Kirkpatrick; John Kirkpatrick; Fannie Kirshner; Eleanor Klee; Helen B. Klimek; Mary Ann Klimik; Beverly Kline; William W. Knight; W.F. Knox; J.E. Koffenberger; Louise Kohms; Verna D. Koiner; David R. Koiner; Stephanie Kojan; George Konoval; Rudolph F. Kopp; Henry Koropal; Henry W. Koropal; Dorothy Ann Kosar; Irving G. Kosch; Nellie A. Kraft; Paul D. Kraus; H.S. Kreiling; B.J. Kristof; Sonya Krondahl; Helen Kruger; Marilyn Kulick; Robert H. Kuczynski; Edna Kyle
- L, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1081)
  Correspondence with Louise Labhard; Theodore Labhard; Nancy Lachester; L.H. Lamborne; Eva C. Lanbach; Dorothy Lancaster; Lancaster County Historical Society; Anna M. Larcom; Vera M. Larson; Charles E. Lauriat; F.W. Law; R.H. Lawrence; Wilbur H. Leadbitter; Edward B. Lee; Elizabeth Lee; Jerry Lee; Marie Lehn; Alfred Leitner; Joseph Lelyveld; Waters School; Mary K. Lenney; Ann D. Leonard; Mabel M. Leonard; Mary Leonard; Nancy Lesko; Joan Leveen; Lester Levy; Alice Lewis; Louise Lewis; Lurline Lewis; Library of Congress; Richard Hill; Notes; Library Journal; Emily H. Kennedy; Maxine Light; Eli Lilly; Ida Sherman Limbird; J.G. Limbird; Ida Sherman Limbird; Rexford J. Lincoln; Lincoln park; Lincoln Park School; Mildred T. Lindaberry; Lindmark Booksellers; Lindmark's; Walter A. Lindwall; H.K. Linnn; M. Linus; S.G. little; Lewis S. Lloyd; Elsie A. Truesdale; Los Angeles Public Library; Richard Loughney; Belknap Campus; Nellda Lorell; Gloria Luchkiu; Gloria Luchkin; Robert W. Lull; Frank Luther; Florence Rader Lutz; H.W. Lynch; Mildred Lynd; Bertha L. Lyons
- Lilly, J.K., 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1082)
- Lilly, J.K. (Black), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1083)
- Mc, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 1084)
  Correspondence with Winifred Mae Demott; Margaert G. MacDonald; Elizabeth Macfarlane; J.R. Macfarlane; Norman MacLeod; Edward Manczuk; M. Marguerute; A.J. Marino; Lewis E. Markle; J.W. Marsh; Aline Martin; J. Stephen Martin; Roscoe B. Martin; Winifred B. Martin; Edna Matz; Gertrude Maxham; John F May; Betty Jane Mayo; W.M. McCaa; M. Isabel McCaffrey; McCann-Erickson; William J. McCashin; John McCaskill; McClees Galleries; Stewart W. McClelland; H.H. McClintic; A.C. McClurg and Company; Orville E. McCollum; Muriel McCord; Muriel E. McCord; Charles L. McCormick; Ethel McCoy; Marie McCracken; Charles McFarland; Howard McFarland; J.W. McGowan; Dorothy McIlroy; William B. McIlvaine; R.C. McKenna; S.E. McKenna; George McKibbin and Son; John A. Shipley; George McKibbin; Garfield McKinney; W.R. McKinney; Mary A. McKissich; J. J. A. McLennan; R. Gerald McMurtry; Charles D. McNaughton
- MA-MU, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1085)
  Correspondence with Earle H. MacLeod; Nancy Mack; Gladys H. Magee; Dillon Edward Mapother; A.J. Marino; Joseph W. Marsh; Mary Marshall; Mary Martin; Richard Martin; Clyde L. Masteller; John E. Matthews; Virginia Megowen; Johanna Meijer; Viola Meints; Ralph Melady; W.L. Mellon; Blaine E. MErcer; Tom Merriman; Jesse Merritt; Eli P. Messenger; Board of Missions and Church, extension of the Methodist Church; The Methodist Publishing House; Nancy C. Mianzo; Ada Holding Miller; Alice M. Miller; Elmer E. Miller; Inez Miller; Lola Miller; Clare Miller; Robert C. Miller; Walter Miller; Charles Millhouse; Harold V. Milligan; Patricia Minich; Minneapolis Public Library; Minnesota Historical Society; Marjorie Minton; Mississippi Valley Historical Review; Hubert Mitchell; Daisie Moats; Lster Ramon Mohr; Mary Lou Mohr; E.F. Montgomery; E.F. Montgomery; W.J. Montgomery; Agnes D. Moore; F.G. Moore; Jack Moore; John Mason Moore; Louise Moore; Robert Moore; Billy R. Moran; Cecil Wentworth Morgan; William Morris Agency; Binnie Morrison; Blanch Moses; Carie Moser; Henry T. Moyer; W.F. Moylan; Margaret Mudrick; Mary M. Mudrick; John E. Muir; Martha E. Mulkey; Joseph Muller; Ralph Munn; Margaret E. Munster; David V. Murdoch; Opal Murphy; William R. Murphy; Foster Murray; Music Dealers Service; Evelyn Musser; Burton H. Mustin
- Morneweck, E.F., 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1086)
  Correspondence with Evelyn Foster Morneweck of Detroit, MI] Morrison Foster's daughter. Lilly first contacted her in 1931. For an undisclosed sum she added some of the most vital pieces to the Collection: Foster's manuscript book, his wallet, etc. In 1932-33, Mrs. Morneweck rendered invaluable assistance to J.T. Howard as he prepared America's Troubadour. During this time she also began The Chronicles of Stephen Foster's Family which wouldn't be completed until 1944. Over the years the correspondence grew to several hundred pieces a year. Many items are factual in nature--checking genealogies, etc--but some letters are filled with rumors, gossip and speculation. Lilly and Morneweck became close friends and were quite open with one another. The 1934 folder, for instance, contains fascinating opinions of Henry Ford as he became embroiled in the White Cottage fiasco. Hodges weeded these files after the moved to Pittsburgh, feeling that certain letters shouldn't be made available to the public. Other letters, because of the valuable factual material they contain, were removed from this correspondence and placed in the collection.
- N, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1087)
  Correspondence with Neiburg,Jack; G.A. Nelson; Henry B. Nelson; Norman J. Nelson; New York Public Library; Dominion of New Zealand; Newbegin's Bookshop; Richard L. Newcomb; M.H. Newton; A. Wayne Nickel; J.B. Nicklas; Maxine Nicolls; Nietzeba; Catherine V. Nimitz; Robert P. Noble; Emma Noell; Mary Martin; Shirley Nagy; F.J. Moles; North Canton Library; Archie Nunnery
- O, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1088)
  Correspondence with Oakhurst School; Salvation Army Ocala Florida; John O'Connor; Margaret O'Connor; Walter O'Day; Marilyn Olenwin; Annabelle Oliver; Robert G. Oliver; Eugene J. Olmi; Clare Olmstead; Robert B. Olsen; Arnold Osborne; Evangeline Ostrom; Edward C. O'Toole
- P, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 1089)
  Correspondence with Joyce Palmer; William F. Palmer; Malcolm Parcell; Jane L. Parker; Carl Parrish; William Parrish; Florence Fisher Parry; Charles H. Pascoe; Margaret K. Patterson; Mildred Pauch; Paul Marie; E.C. Payne; Mary M. Payne; E.R. Payne; Joseph J. Pearce; Charles A. Peloquin; R.N. Williams; Hotel Pennsylvania; Pentland Bookshap; Margaret Pepper; Claire Ann Perry; John L. Perry; Esther E. Peters; H.M. Peterson; John E. Peterson; Milton A. Peterson; Petworth School; Philadelphia Autograph Company; Charles A. Philhower; Alfred N. Phillips; F.J. Phillips; Pickwick Bookshop; Louis Epslein; Camillus L. Pierle; Salie Piner; M. Pirl; Pittsburgh News Company; George F. Pollard; A.G. Popcke; Lowell Pope; Library Association of Portland; Frank J. Potts; Eveline Pouder; Inez Powell; Earl T. Prange; Morse M. Preeman; Presbyterian Book Store; Gerald R. Prescott; H.F. Prescott; Harry T. Prescott; Jean Pribodka; Nancy Ann Price; O. K. Price; R.L. Prince; The Publishers Weekly; Doris Pulaski; Purdue University
- Pittsburgh, University of, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 1090)
  Correspondence with W. Harry Archer; University Bookstore; William Farmer; T.M. Finney; Theodore M. Finney; Wendell Gullion; James Hagan; Albert A. Klimcheck; Ruth Crawford Mitchell; Ralph Mitterling; J.W. Oliver; Francis Joseph Putman; A,L, Robinson; Marjorie Todd; E. Sommer; C.V. Starrett; Agnes Starrett; Helen S. McConnell; Buell B. Whitehill
- Pittsburgh, University of (John G. Bowman), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1091)
- Pittsburgh, University of (Fitzgerald), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1092)
- Pittsburgh, University of (Inter Office), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1093)
  Correspondence with B.B. Corson
- Pittsburgh, University of (Press), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1094)
  Correspondence with Wendell Gullion Manager of the University of Pittsburgh Press
- Pittsburgh, University of (G.S. Rupp), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1095)
- Pittsburgh, University of (John Weber), 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1096)
- Q, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1097)
  Correspondence with C. Agnes Quin
- Republic Bank Note Co., 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1098)
- R, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1099)
  Correspondence with Ethel Rabich; D.G. Rafferty; Alma C. Ramsey; George Randalph; Random House; R.A. Feiman; Harley C. Ransom; Enoch Rauh; Wm. C. Rapp; Lou E. Ballenger; harold P. Reading; C.M. Redman; Ernest A. Reed; Marshall Foster Reed; Eugene Reichenfeld; Wayne Reiner; Arthur H. Renier; Mary Law Renner; William A. Renshaw; Benjamin Renzi; John Rhodes; Donald Richards; Mary Richards; Frances A. Richardson; Joseph Richardson; Leo Richardson; H.H. Richmond; C.W. Ridinger; W.L. Riggs; Harold V. Riley; Mary Elizabeth Riley; Patsy Ritch; George O. Ritcher; Leon Robbin; W. Roertson; Donald F. Robey; A.C. Robinson; A.C. Robinson; George M. Robinson; J.M. Robinson; Robert M. Prentice; Patricia Ann Robinson; Maud F. Roby; Kenneth J. Rodewald; Florence M. Rogers; Lucille Rogers; Betty Roine; A.D. Romig; Harry Rooney; Janice Root; Elisha Rosanova; Dallas C. Rose; Floyd Rose; Howard E. Rose; Jessie Welch Rose; Kenneth Rose; Viola Rose; M.C. Rosenberry; Donald W. Rossman; Rebecca Rosson; Allan Roth; Reid M. Rowan; J.M. Royston; Leon T. Rubinstein; George V. Rumreich; Joseph R. Ryan
- S, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1100)
  Correspondence with St. John Evangelist Convent; St. Joseph's School; St. Mary's Convent; St. Mary's School; St. Paul Book and Stationary Co.; Service Club; Vincent Sala; M. Salome; Blanche Salter; Charles S. Samarjian; Smyrna High School; Sylvia Sanders; San Francisco News Company; Carlos J. Sapp; Watkins A. Saunders; W.A. Sausaman; William Orr Sawyers; R.C. Sayre; A.M. Scaife; Frederic Schaefer; John F. Schaefer; L. Dale Schaefer; Mary Louise Scharar; Judith Schiff; G. Schirmer; Selma Cole; Gloria Schlenken; Schmoller and Mueller Piano Co.; Reynold Schneck; Douglas Schoerke; Alice M. Schramm; Anna L. Schramm; Albert Schutt; Gertrude Schwalbe; Irving Schwartz; Jean Schweitzer; Harry Ray Schewender; Philip S. Sciscoes; Edith B. Scofield; The Scribner Book Store; Charles Scribner's Sons; Raymond Scrivner; Scruggs Vandervoort Barney Inc.; Arthur M. Scully; Robert Seabock; Ruth Segur; George W. Selke; Laurence L. Selke; Ken Sentney; Rose Serrae; Dorothy Setmar; Gladys Cox Seymour; Mildred Shaddix; James D. Shaner; Elliott Shapiro; Shawnee Centralized Schools; Alexander Sherman; William T. Sherman School; Clarice Shoffner; Gale Siemon; Anoinette Siessmayer; Edward Simmons; J.O. Simonds; Stephen L. Simqu; J.L. Sinclair; C.A. Swinger; Brooks N. Sipes; Arthur B. Siviater; Frederick W. Skiff; Frank J. Slatery; Earl Hobson Smith; Edna J. Smith; Floyd A. Smith; James A. Smith; William Galbraith Smith; W.W. Smith; Jerome Snyder; Lizetta D. Snyder; W.P. Snyder; Gertrude Soeurt; Richard S. Sollman; Vernon B. Sones; Southern Music Co.; Charles S. Spaulding; A.J. Sparaco; A.W. Spencer; Jacqueline Spiegel; Frank C. Springer; Ora Spronl; Robert Gordon Sproul; Lloyd S. Sprowles; A.B. Squires; Ralph A. Stabile; Margaret Stacy; F.W. Stahl; L.D. Starus; John Stalter; Jessa M. Stanford; Grace D. Stearns; Bessie Stebick; G.E. Stechert; R.G. Stevens; B.F. Stevens; Alexander Stewart; J.A. Stewart; H. Spencer Stillwagon; Polly Stoddard; Vincent F. Stoll; Malcom N. Stone; Norma Stone; Robert L. Stringer; Glada N. Strode; Gale F. Stroup; Dorlene Stubbins; Edward R. Sullivan; Richard Sullivan; Emma Surra; Joan Suydam; Mackey Swan; Arthur M. Swimmer; Constance Sykes; M. Sylvester; Helen Szastak
- T, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1101)
  Correspondence with John Taggart; Mary Lou Talbot; Axel W. Tall; Anna Faith Taylor; R.W. Taylor; Ruby M. Taylor; S.A. Taylor; Lt. Taxman; James W. Tebay; William G. Tempel; Marie Teresa; William Thaw; Jean Thoburn; Earl Thomas; Thomas F. Thompson; Albert Thorne; Alexander F. Thornton; George Crosman Thornton; Henry Thornton; William Foster Thornton; John H. Tilden; A.A. Tinklenberg; Richard B. Tobias; Louise Tomlinson; Anna R. Toothill; F.K. Tovey; Isabel Townsend; J.C. Trees; W.F. Trimble; Betty Trimmer; Anthony R. Trovant; Phyllis G. Truchses; Ruth M. Tubbs; Mary E. Turney; Turtle Creek Borough School District
- Townsend, John Wilson, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1102)
- U, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1103)
  Correspondence with Jennie Ufnar; Walter E. Ulich; Roy Umble; Arthur J.C. Underhill; Eldred C. Upp; Joan Uram
- V, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1104)
  Correspondence with George A. Valentine; Jacqueline Van Billiard; Everett Vandever; Marilyn Varga; Ruth Varga; Richard S. Vaughan; Howard Verbeck; Genevieve Virro; Raoul Georges Vidas; Carl P. Viviton; Carl P. Vinton; M. Viola; Virginia State Library; Louise Savage; Louis Voelker; Betty Vogel; William Leist; Kenneth C. Volpp; Maurine Vonier; A.C. Vroman
- W, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1105)
  Correspondence with Rosalie Wade; C.E. Wager; Harry Wait; Mae Walker; James H. Wall; Alfred Wallace; Ruth E. Wallgren; Andrew Walleck; Mary Albert Ward; Jay W. Warner; Warner Brothers; Donald R. Watson; George E. Watson; Bennie H. Weaver; Edythe Webster; M.D. Wedgworth; E.R. Weidlein; Helen Weidner; R.G. Weigel; Mary Weinsheiner; J.R. Weldin; James Earl Wells; Matthew Wiley Welsh; Walter William Wendling; Ethelyn Wenzlaff; Esther Wescoat; Agnes A. West; Westchester Features Syndicate; Westchester Features Syndicate; Westinghouse Electric Supply Company; Westmoreland Observer; Westwood Book Store; Margaret Whallen; Carolyn Wheeler; Emma Lewis Whitaker; Samuel H. Whitaker; Mackey W. White; Mackey W. White; White Springs; Buell B. Whitehill; E.T. Whiter; C.W. Whitmore; G.D. Whitney; Bliss Wiant; W. Paull Wible; Anton J. Wichmann; Gertrude Wieckoski; Joyce Wieser; Elizabeth Wightman; Stephen J. Wigmore; Raymond T. Wilber; Eleanor Wilby; Eleanor S. Wilby; Hazel Wilcox; Wilcox and Follett; Lyman W. Newlin Business Manager; Loren Wilham; H.R. Wilkins; Nancy Wilkinson; Jean Williams; Joseph C. Williams; Albeta E. Wilson; Estelle Wilson; Irene Wilson; Mary C. Wilson; Wilson and Harbison; Samuel M. Wilson; S.R. Wilson; Albert T. Winkelmann; Lois Wisell; Nora JEan Withrow; W. Paull Wivle; William Woestehoff; Calvin Wonderly; Catherine B. Wood; Donald Woodrow; Charlie A. Woods; Woodsworth's Book Store; C.L. Wooldridge; Evelyn Woolslayer; Audrey M. Worthge; Wren Village School; Carol Ann Wright; Frank K. Wylie; Vaughn E. Wyman
- Wilson, Mary Alice, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1106)
- X, Y, Z, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1107)
  Correspondence with Marylin Yocum; Richard Yaracs; Aletha C. Young; J.U. Young; Lewis E. Young; Nancy Young; William W. Young; J.P. Youngberg; Robert Mae Youngling; David Leory Yount; Mary Ann Yram; Muriel Zabriskie; Bonnie Zahn; Robert C. Zander; Irvin E. Zimmerman; J. McC. Zimmerman; Joan Zotter; William Henry Zwiesler
- Foster Hall Payroll, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1108)
  Hours worked and amounts paid to various staff at Foster Hall
- Foster Hall Collection Schedules, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1109)
- University of Pittsburgh material, Foster Hall Collection acquisitions, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 1110)